# Matteo Bertrone

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER · RESEARCH ASSISTANT AT POLYTECHNIC OF TURIN

24, Corso Duca degli Abruzzi, Turin, Italy 10129

🛘 (+39) 334 798-6923 | 🗷 m.bertrone@gmail.com | 😭 mbertrone.github.io | 🖸 mbertrone | 🛅 bertrone

"Everyone thinks of changing the world, but no one thinks of changing himself" - Leo Tolstoy



### Summary\_

I'm research assistant at Department of Control and Computer Engineering of Polytechnic of Turin, Italy, where I'm working on network programmability, SDN and could computing, eXpress Data Path (XDP) and eBPF. I deal with distributed programming, APIs design, concurrency, and performance optimization. I love to code, but I also love to share ideas and feedback with my team, not only technical ones.

# Work Experience\_

### **Polytechnic of Turin**

Turin, Italy

RESEARCH FELLOW & SOFTWARE ENGINEER - USED LANGUAGES (C++, EBPF, GO)

- Jan. 2017 PRESENT
- Core developer of Polycube: I am part of design and development process of the framework from the very beginning.
- Implemented an abstraction layer to easily deploy services (e.g. bridges, routers), configure them, create virtual topologies, and connect them to Dockers, namespaces, VMs, NICs. Developed a rich set of services, e.g. bridge, router, load balancer, nat, DDoS mitigator.
- Designed and developed a clone of iptables firewall, exploiting efficient algorithms and XDP optimizations, leading up to 10x performance gain.

#### **Huawei Technologies**

Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

INTERN - USED LANGUAGES (C++, EBPF, Go)

May. 2018 - Jun. 2018

• Development of Polycube framework and services, as collaboration with Polytechnic of Turin.

### Nebbiolo Technologies, INC. (Start-up company)

CONSULTANT - USED LANGUAGES (C++, EBPF, GO)

Milpitas, CA, U.S.A. Feb. 2017 - May. 2017

• Design and deploy of a lightweight bridging networking solution, as a substitute of Linux bridge.

### PLUMgrid INC. (Acquired by VMware)

Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

INTERN - USED LANGUAGES (EBPF, Go)

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2017

• Developed a networking provider for OpenStack. Increased visibility by publishing it under iovisor community.

## EiSWORLD

Turin, Italy

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - USED LANGUAGES (C#)

Mar. 2014 - May. 2014

• Developed a network analysis and diagnostic tool for Fiat Chrysler Automobiles, used to debug and detect issues on dealers network.

# Projects & Open Source

### **PolyCube**

github.com/polycube-network

CORE DEVELOPER - POLYCUBE IS AN OPEN SOURCE FRAMEWORK TO BUILD VIRTUAL NETWORK FUNCTIONS WITH XDP AND EBPF

Jan. 2017 - PRESENT

lovisor-ovn

github.com/iovisor/iovisor-ovn

MAIN DEVELOPER - IOVISOR-OVN PROVIDES AN EFFICIENT DATA PLANE REPLACEMENT FOR OPENSTACK NETWORKING.

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2017

### Publications

### **Accelerating Linux Security with eBPF iptables**

Budapest, Hungary

ACM SIGCOMM 2018 CONFERENCE POSTERS AND DEMOS

20-25 August 2018

Toward an eBPF-based clone of iptables

Montréal, Canada

NETDEV 0X12, THE TECHNICAL CONFERENCE ON LINUX NETWORKING

11-13 July 2018

Creating Complex Network Services with eBPF: Experience and Lessons Learned

Bucharest, Romania

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON HIGH PERFORMANCE SWITCHING AND ROUTING

17-20 June 2018

### **Presentation**

#### **Open vSwitch Fall Conference**

San Jose, CA, U.S.A.

DEMO - COUPLING THE FLEXIBILITY OF OVN WITH THE EFFICIENCY OF IOVISOR: ARCHITECTURE AND DEMO

Nov. 2016

### Education

#### **Polytechnic of Turin**

Turin, Italy

MASTER'S DEGREE, COMPUTER ENGINEERING, 110/110

2014 - 2016 Turin, Italy

Polytechnic of Turin

2011 - 2014

BSC Degree, Computer Engineering, 110/110

JANUARY 10, 2019 MATTEO BERTRONE · RÉSUMÉ